Yang, Bo

Developer

3

+1-415-420-9693



https://yang-bo.com



pop.atry@gmail.com



pop_atry



yang_bo



955091



Atry

About me -

I am a developer who knows how to create application frameworks.

I founded various open-source projects for creating micro-services, neural networks, reactive GUIs, and DSLs, which are stared 3000+ times on Github.

My current interesting is machine learning engineering or development in functional programming languages, especially for creating developer tools or frameworks.

Skills

Scala

Machine Learning

Software Design

Agile Project Management

Hack *5.5 Haxe *5.5 OpenCL *5
DevOps *5 ActionScript *4
C++ *4 Java *4 JavaScript *4
Rust *4 OCaml *4 Testing *3
C *3 Spark *3 Akka *3

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Open-source projects

2021-2022 HHVM C++/Rust/OCaml is Meta's virtual machine running Hack. I ported the open source branch of HHVM to Nix and created CI pipeline for building, testing, and packaging HHVM.

since 2018 Dsl.scala Scala is a framework to extend Scala language features in libraries. I also ported this framework to Haskell as Control.Dsl.

since 2016 DeepLearning.scala and Compute.scala Scala are libraries for creating complex neural networks.

since 2015 Binding.scala Scala is a reactive templating language for creating web and desktop GUI.

2015-2016 Microbuilder Haxe / Scala / Java / JavaScript

is a toolkit that helps you build system across micro-services implemented in various languages communicating via RESTful JSON API.

since 2012 haxe-continuation Haxe

provides async/await syntax for Haxe.

since 2010 protoc-gen-as3 ActionScript3

is a Protocol Buffers plugin for ActionScript 3.

since 2007 other 100+ of open-source projects

Publications

2017 DeepLearning.scala 2.0: Statically Typed Neural Networks

2017 More than React

2009 Adobe Flex 3: Training from the Source (translator)

Talks

2017	Deeplearning.Scala——Thoughts and practices	s on open source deep
	learning framework	DBTC
2017	Monadic Deep Learning	Strange Loop
2017	Neural Networks & Functional Programming	ArchData Summit · Beijing
2016	More than Async	QCon · Beijing
2015	Specific-domain extension in an universal lang	uage ECUG Con

Experience

2019-2022 Meta Platforms Inc Software Developer
I built machine learning infrastructure to detect fraud in payments and integrate it into

various products. Then I moved to Hack/HHVM OSS team, maintaining HHVM's open

source branch.

2015-2019 Thoughtworks Inc Senior Consultant / Lead Consultant I maintained some open-source projects sponsored by ThoughtWorks. I also took the

I maintained some open-source projects sponsored by ThoughtWorks. I also took the role of consultant or technical leader in various delivery teams for creating mobile and

web applications and data platforms.

2014 Shenzhen QiFun Network Corp., LTD Chief Programmer

I led the Q-Force Team in developing game engine along with its related tools, and two

mobile games.

2011-2013 Shenzhen Putaoteng Network Technology Co., Ltd. Co-founder

I led the start-up team in developing a 3D side-scrolling game engine VinyHome and a

social game Nan Da Nu Pei.

2008-2011 NetEase, Inc. Chief Programmer

I participated in various product teams as a developer or the technical lead, including Zhan Guo Feng Yun (web game), Ka Pai Dui Jue (web game), Deepcold (3D game

engine).

2007 Beijing HiPiHi Information Technology Corp.,Ltd Software Engineer

I developed variant components of both client-side and server-side for a 3D virtual

world, HiPiHi World.

2006-2007 Beijing AutoNavi Software Co., Ltd. Software Engineer

As a developer, I developed some components for a 3D navigation software.

Education

2002-2006 Southwest University of Political Science and Law Bachelor Of Laws